Edwin J. Feulner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Other Professional Files, 1947-2003 (Box 743-800)
  - Subject file
    - Institute of Economic Affairs, 1967-1974
    - International Management and Development Institute, 1975-1977
    - Iron Curtain humor, 1964-1969 (Box 798)
    - Kuehnelt-Leddihn, Erik von, 1966-1971
    - Latin America, 1966-1968, (3 folders)
    - Miscellaneous topics, 1964-1975
    - National Alternative Inner City Futures Project, 1975
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1965-1967
    - Nutter, G. Warren, 1967-1969
    - Panama Canal, 1967
    - Rail passenger service, 1968
    - Rally magazine, 1965-1967
    - Republican Coordinating Committee, 1965-1968
    - Revenue sharing, 1967-1971, (3 folders) (Box 799)
    - Rhodesia, 1967-1970
    - Shub, Anatole, "Russia Turns Back the Clock," series of articles, 1969
    - South Africa, 1963-1975, (2 folders)
    - Soviet and satellite economies, 1965-1971, (3 folders)
    - Soviet Union, 1967-1971 (Box 800)
    - Sutton, Anthony C., 1969-1970
    - Transportation Research Forum, 1965-1970
    - Union for Radical Political Economics, 1969, (2 folders)
    - United Nations General Assembly, 1982, 2003
    - United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy, swearing in of Feulner, 1982
    - Washington Report, American Security Council, 1966-1971, (3 folders)
  - Walton Company, transportation project for Richard Cornuelle, 1966
- Speech and Trip Files, 1958-2014 (Box 801-862)
  Speeches and drafts, itineraries, agendas, conference packets, correspondence, invitations, printed matter, memorabilia, photographs, and other material pertaining to events, speaking engagements, and trips attended by Feulner.
  Arranged chronologically by year and therein by month and day of event.
  - 1958, 1965-1967, (9 folders) (Box 801)
  - 1968, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 802)
  - 1969-1972, (10 folders)
  - 1974-1975, (7 folders) (Box 803)
  - 1976
    - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
    - Aug.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 804)
    - Miscellany
  - 1977
    - May-Aug., (3 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 805)
    - Miscellany
  - 1978
    - Feb.-June, (4 folders)
    - June-July, (2 folders) (Box 806)
    - July-Dec., (6 folders)
    - Miscellany
  - 1979, (9 folders) (Box 807)
  - 1980
    - Feb.
    - Mar.-Sept., (8 folders) (Box 808)
    - Sept.-Oct.
    - Oct. (Box 809)
    - Miscellany
  - 1981
    - Jan.-May, (11 folders)
    - June-Dec., (11 folders) (Box 810)
    - Interviews
    - Miscellany
  - 1982 (Box 811)
    - Feb.-June, (11folders)
    - July-Sept., (8 folders) (Box 812)
    - Oct. (Box 813)
    - Miscellany
  - 1983
    - Jan.-Feb., (5 folders)
    - Mar., (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 814)
    - Apr.-Oct., (8 folders)
    - Miscellany
  - 1984
    - Jan.
    - Feb.-July, (12 folders) (Box 815)
    - Sept.-Oct., (3 folders) (Box 816)
    - Miscellany
  - 1985
    - Jan-Mar., (7 folders)
    - Apr.-July, (7 folders) (Box 817)
    - July-Aug.
    - Aug.-Nov., (7 folders) (Box 818)
    - Miscellany
  - 1986
    - Feb.
    - Mar.-July, (9 folders) (Box 819)
    - Aug.-Sept., (6 folders) (Box 820)
    - Sept.-Oct., (3 folders) (Box 821)
    - Nov.
    - Miscellany
  - 1987
    - Jan.-Mar., (6 folders)
    - Apr.-Nov., (16 folders) (Box 822)
    - Miscellany (Box 823)
  - 1988
    - Jan.-Apr., (6 folders)
    - June, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 824)
    - June-July
    - July-Oct., (5 folders)
    - Miscellany
  - 1989
    - Jan.-Mar., (6 folders)
    - Apr.-Sept., (12 folders) (Box 825)
    - Oct.-Nov., (6 folders) (Box 826)
    - Miscellany
  - 1990
    - Jan.-May, (10 folders)
    - June-Dec., (8 folders) (Box 827)
    - Miscellany
  - 1991
    - Mar., (3 folders)
    - Apr.-Dec., (13 folders) (Box 828)
    - Interview
    - Miscellany (Box 829)
  - 1992
    - Jan.-Aug., (14 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (10 folders) (Box 830)
    - Miscellany, (2 folders)
  - 1993 (Box 831)
    - Jan.-Mar., (7 folders)
    - Apr.-June, (5 folders) (Box 832)
    - July-Sept., (6 folders) (Box 833)
    - Oct.-Nov., (5 folders) (Box 834)
    - Miscellany
  - 1994
    - Jan., (1 folder) (Box 835)
    - Feb.-Mar., (6 folders)
    - Mar.-Apr. (Box 836)
    - Apr.-May, (6 folders)
    - June-Aug., (8 folders) (Box 837)
    - Oct.-Nov., (5 folders) (Box 838)
    - Miscellany (Box 839)
  - 1995
    - Jan.-Feb., (7 folders)
    - Mar., (2 folders) (Box 840)
    - Apr.-June, (10 folders)
    - July-Sept., (4 folders) (Box 841)
    - Oct., (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box 842)
    - Nov., (3 folders)
    - Miscellany (Box 843)
  - 1996
    - Jan.-Feb., (6 folders)
    - Mar.-June, (9 folders) (Box 844)
    - Oct.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box 845)
    - Miscellany
  - 1997
    - Jan.-Mar., (10 folders)
    - Apr.-June, (11 folders) (Box 846)
    - June-July, (3 folders)
    - July-Dec., (8 folders) (Box 847)
    - Miscellany
  - 1998
    - Jan., (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 848)
    - Feb.-Mar., (6 folders)
    - Apr., (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 849)
    - May-Aug., (5 folders)
    - Oct.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 850)
    - Miscellany
  - 1999
    - Jan.
    - Feb.-Mar., (5 folders) (Box 851)
    - Apr., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 852)
    - May-Aug., (8 folders)
    - Sept.-Dec., (12 folders) (Box 853)
    - Miscellany, (2 folders)
  - 2000, (14 folders) (Box 854)
  - 2001, (15 folders) (Box 855)
  - 2002, (15 folders) (Box 856)
  - 2003-2004, (11 folders) (Box 857)
  - 2005- 2007, (12 folders) (Box 858)
  - 2008-2010, (7 folders) (Box 859)
  - 2011
    - Jan.-Apr., (4 folders)
    - June-Nov., (4 folders) (Box 860)
    - Miscellany, (2 folders)
  - 2012, (3 folders)
  - 2013-2014, (5 folders) (Box 861)
  - Undated
    - Fragments
    - Miscellany
  - Reference file
    - 1976-1990, (3 folders)
    - 1993-2004, undated, (8 folders) (Box 862)
- Writings, 1934-2013 (Box 862-897)
  Articles and columns, book reviews, books, a dissertation, drafts, essays, manuscripts, card files, contracts, correspondence, notes, and research material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of writing or material and therein alphabetically or chronologically.
  - Articles and columns (Box 862)
    - 1962-1974, (2 folders)
    - 1975-1997, (9 folders) (Box 863)
    - 1998-2013, undated, (10 folders) (Box 864)
  - Audiotape review, 1975 (Box 865)
  - Book file material, 1986-1991, undated
  - Book reviews, 1962-1969, 2011, (2 folders)
  - Books
    - The American Spirit: Celebrating the Virtues and Values that Make Us Great, publishing agreement, 2010
    - China-The Turning Point
      - Correspondence, 1976
      - Drafts, circa 1976, (3 folders)
      - Research and notes, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 866)
    - Congress and the New International Economic Order
      - Correspondence, 1975-1976
      - Drafts
        - General, circa 1976
        - Revised, 1976, (2 folders)
      - Foreign reactions to the New International Economic Order, 1975 (Box 867)
      - Page proofs, 1976
      - Published volume, 1976
      - Research and notes, 1970-1977, undated, (4 folders)
    - Conservatives Stalk the House: The Republican Study Committee
      - Amended pages, 1982
      - Card file, undated (Box OV 868)
      - Correspondence and contract, 1981-1983, undated (Box 869)
      - Drafts, undated, (3 folders)
      - Library of Congress cataloging data sheet, 1983 (Box 870)
      - Mailing lists, undated
      - Manuscript revisions and notes, 1973-1982, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1983, undated
      - Page proofs
        - Bibliography and index, undated
        - First, 1982, Nov. 15
          - Set 1, (2 folders)
          - Set 2
        - First revised, 1983, Feb. 18 (Box 871)
          - Set 1, (2 folders)
          - Set 2, (2 folders)
    - Economic Strategy in War and Peace, unpublished
      - General, 1949, 1974-1975, undated, (3 folders)
      - Chapter I: Introduction, 1935, 1966, 1975, undated
      - Chapter II: The Lesson of History, 1974
    - Getting America Right: The True Conservative Values Our Nation Needs Today, 2006 (Box 872)
      - Planning Workbook: Vol. II, Book Tour and Regional Marketing Plans
      - Website
    - Intellectual Pilgrims: The Fiftieth Anniversary of the Mont Pelerin Society, correspondence, 1999-2000
    - March of Freedom: Modern Classics in Conservative Thought, 1996-1998, undated, (4 folders)
    - Quiet Revolution, drafts
      - Chapters 1-10, 1992
      - Chapters 1-13, circa 1992 (Box 873)
      - Chapters 1-13 with inserts, circa 1992
    - Trading with the Communists
      - Bibliography, circa 1967
      - Correspondence and review, 1967-1968, undated
      - Drafts
        - 1968
        - Undated (Box 874)
      - Research, 1934, 1954, 1962-1967, undated, (3 folders)
    - Untitled, 1985-1991
  - Chapters for books
    - "East-West Trade and the Vietnam War" in Readings on East-West Trade, 1971
    - "The Economic Factor as a National Security Tool" in United States National Security Policy in the Decade Ahead
      - Correspondence, 1976-1978
      - Drafts
        - Early, 1976
        - Miscellaneous, undated
        - Typed, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 875)
      - Research
        - Arab boycott, 1975-1976
        - Commodity agreement, 1976
        - East-West trade, 1974-1976
        - Export controls, 1976
        - Foreign aid, United States and Soviet Union, 1976-1977
        - General, 1974-1976
        - Grain sales, 1975-1976
        - Law of the Sea, 1976
        - Multinationals, 1976
        - Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries, 1974-1976
        - Private loans to less developed countries, 1976
        - Rhodesian chrome, 1973-1976 (Box 876)
        - United States food weapon, 1975-1976
        - World food, 1975-1976
    - "Executive-Legislation Relations and U.S. Defense Policy" from unpublished book
      - Correspondence and drafts, 1977-1978
      - Research, 1951-1977, undated, (2 folders)
    - "The Heritage Foundation" in Think Tanks in Civil Societies, 1997-1998
    - "Recent Congressional Developments in Trading with Eastern Europe" in American-Eastern European Trade: Controversy, Progress, Prospects, 1969
  - Contracts and correspondence, 1985-2004, 2012, undated
  - Dissertation, "Evolution of the Republican Study Committee" (Box OV 877)
    - Card file, undated
    - Corrections, undated (Box 878)
    - Drafts
      - Chapter outlines, 1976-1978, undated, (2 folders)
      - Footnotes
        - Chapters I-VIII, undated
        - Chapter I-III, VII, undated
        - Chapter VI, 1981
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1979-circa 1981, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 879)
      - Set A
        - Chapter I
          - First draft, 1980
          - First draft with comments, 1980
          - Second draft, 1980
          - Second draft with comments, 1980
          - Third draft, 1981
        - Chapter II
          - Possible first draft, 1979
          - Second draft original, 1980
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
        - Chapter III (Box 880)
          - Second draft, 1979
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
          - Third draft read, 1981
          - Fourth draft, 1981
        - Chapter IV, third draft with comments, 1980
        - Chapter V
          - Possible first draft, 1979
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
          - Third draft revised, 1980
          - Fourth draft read, 1981
          - Rough draft, 1981 (Box 881)
        - Chapter VI
          - First draft with comments, 1980
          - Second draft original, 1979
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
          - Fourth draft original, 1980
          - Fourth draft read, 1981
        - Chapter VII
          - First draft original, 1979
          - Second draft, 1979
          - Second draft original, 1979 (Box 882)
          - Third draft, 1980
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
        - Chapter VIII
          - First rough draft, 1979
          - Third draft, 1980
          - Third draft with comments, 1980
      - Set B, undated
        - Chapters I-II, (2 folders)
        - Chapter III-VIII, (7 folders) (Box 883)
        - Additional material (Box 884)
      - Set C, 1980, (2 folders)
      - Set D, undated, (2 folders)
      - Set E, circa 1981 (Box 885)
    - Notes
      - Backup, undated
      - Books, undated
      - Chapters, 1979-1980, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1973-1981, undated
      - To and from Feulner, 1980-1981, undated
    - References, 1966, 1974, undated
    - Research
      - Chapter III, early case studies
        - Child care, 1971, undated
        - Welfare reform, 1969-1979
      - Chapter IV
        - Articles, 1973-1978
        - Correspondence, 1972-1977, undated
        - Kingston Group, 1973-1974
        - Memoranda, 1973-1978, undated (Box 886)
        - Memoranda to the file, 1973-1975, undated, (4 folders)
        - Red Fox I and Red Fox II meetings See Container 483, same heading
        - Republican Study Committee
          - Congress, 1973-1978
          - Papers, 1973-1974, undated
          - Staff, 1973-1976, undated
        - Senate Steering Committee, 1974
      - Chapter VI
        - 1975 files, 1975
        - Budget seminar, 1974-1977, (2 folders) (Box 887)
        - Folder A, 1975-1977
        - Folder B, 1974-1977
        - Folder C, 1975
        - Folder D, 1975-1976, undated
        - Folder E, 1974-1976, undated
        - Folder F, 1975-1979
        - Folder G, 1975-1976 (Box 888)
        - Folder H, 1975-1977, (3 folders)
        - Folder I, 1974-1976, undated
        - Folder J, 1975-1976, undated
        - General, 1975-1977
        - National Security Group, 1976
      - Chapter VII (Box 889)
        - Case studies, unions, 1975, undated
        - Consumer Protection Agency, 1974-1977
        - Welfare reform, 1974-1976, undated
      - Congressional groups, 1969-1978
      - Miscellany
        - 1964-1972, (3 folders)
        - 1973-1975, (4 folders) (Box 890)
        - 1976-1978, (3 folders) (Box 891)
        - 1979-1983, (3 folders) (Box 892)
        - Undated (Box 893)
    - Status reports on chapters, undated
    - University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland
      - Correspondence, 1977-1981
      - Notebook on interviews, 1979-1981
  - Essays
    - "Agrarian Reform in Latin America," 1967
    - "A Challenge to the American Business Community," 1967
    - "The Determination of International Air Fares," 1965-1967, (1 folder) (Box 894)
    - "The Failure of the British Railway System," 1965
    - "Individualism and Freedom in an Automated Age," 1963
    - "A New Look at Devaluation," circa 1963
    - "The Prospects of Convergence," 1967
    - "Soviet Economic Reforms," 1966
    - "The Soviet Transportation System," 1966
  - Forewords and introductions, 1982, 1994-1999, 2005, 2011-2014, (2 folders)
  - Guest editor, Washington Report, 1967-1968
  - Letters to the editor, 1964-1965, 1971-1979, 1985
  - Manuscripts, United Nations, 1975, (5 folders) (Box 895)
  - Miscellany, circa 2011, undated
  - National Public Policy Syndicate, 1978-1979
  - Outlines, 1966, 1974, undated
  - Research material (Box 896)
    - Set A
      - 1951, 1959, 1968-1975, (5 folders)
      - 1976, (1 folder) (Box 897)
      - Undated and fragments
    - Set B
      - I. Introduction, 1975
      - III. Framework for Control of U.S. Exports and Concerted Action, 1974-1975, undated
      - IV. Role of Economic Warfare Today, 1973-1975, undated
      - V. Energy and Cartels, 1975
      - VI. Minerals, 1974-1975
      - VII. Food, 1974-1975
- Digital Files, 1996-2005 (Box DF)
  Audio files, video files, and text files. The files are copied from a variety of storage media. Each media was assigned a unique digital ID number. Request files using the digital ID number. For file directory listings of each storage media, see Appendix A: File Directory Listings.
  Arranged into the following subseries: Set A and Set B. Set A files are from storage media found within the paper files in the course of processing. Set B files are from storage media received independent of the paper files. The series comprises 108 files and 17.6 GB.
  - Set A, 2004-2005 (Box DF)
    Two video files attached to letters sent to Feulner. These files were extracted from optical disks. A container number and folder description are provided as a reference to the original location in the paper files. Each media was assigned a unique digital ID number. Request files using the digital ID number.
    Arranged and described according to the series, container, and folders from which the items were removed.
    - Heritage Foundation (Box DF)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 2004
            - Israel Center for Social & Economic Progress, Sam Zell's Visit 2004, attached to a letter of 22 June 2004, from Daniel Doron to Feulner, with reply letter from Feulner of 15 July 2004 (Container 306, folder 1 of 2), mss85758_140_011
          - 2005
            - Interview of Michael D. Antonovich on his children and the family by Clifton Davis attached to a letter of 15 Mar. 2005, from Antonovich to Feulner, with reply letter from Feulner of 5 Apr. 2005 (Container 308, 2005, Apr.), mss85758_140_012
  - Set B, 1996-2009 (Box DF)
    Audio files, video files, and text files. The audio and video files show speeches, introductory remarks, and interviews given by Feulner and his appearance on various discussion panels. These files were extracted from optical disks. The text files from the 1996 vice presidential campaign of Jack Kemp are Word and WordPerfect document files. Another text file is a WordPerfect document listing appointments to the various committees of the Board of Trustees at the Heritage Foundation in 1998. These files were extracted from 3.5" floppy disks. Set B files are from storage media received independent of the paper files. Each media was assigned a unique digital ID number. Request files using the digital ID number.
    - List of campaign contacts for vice presidential campaign of Jack Kemp, 1996, mss85758_140_009 (Box DF)
    - Notes from meetings on 21 September 1996 held with Paul M. Weyrich and the Family Research Council and a list of names and addresses, 1996, relating to vice presidential campaign of Jack Kemp, mss85758_140_010
    - Talking points on Index of Economic Freedom, 1-2 Dec. 1998, for speech delivered by Feulner in Asia, mss85758_140_013
    - List of appointments to the committees of the Board of Trustees of the Heritage Foundation, 16 Apr. 1998, mss85758_140_014
    - Interview of Feulner by Milinda Moragoda on program "In Black and White" concerning Heritage Foundation. Sri Lanka, 2004, Jan., mss85758_140_017
    - Talk given by Feulner on the book Getting America Right: The True Conservative Values Our Nation Needs Today that he coauthored with Doug Wilson. Council on National Policy, McLean, Va., 2006 May 11-13, mss85758_140_002
    - Feulner as panelist on "What Next for the Conservative Movement? What Next for the Republican Party?" Council on National Policy, Amelia Island, Fla., 2007, Feb. 1-3, mss85758_140_004
    - Feulner as moderator of panel "The Three-Legged Stool of Conservatism." Council on National Policy, Minneapolis, Minn., 2008, Aug. 27-29, mss85758_140_005
    - Feulner as one of the hosts/speakers at "Salute to Paul Weyrich: His Life, Work & Mission." Washington, D.C., 2008, Sept. 10, mss85758_140_006
    - Feulner speaking "The Heritage Foundation Pennsylvania Avenue Building," explaining the necessity of acquiring the building in January 2008, Washington D.C.?, circa 2008, mss85758_140_001
    - Feulner and others presenting "A Tribute to Paul Weyrich." Council on National Policy, Washington, D.C., 2009, May 14-16, mss85758_140_007
    - Feulner presenting "The Obama Administration: An Analysis of the First 100 Days." Council on National Policy, Washington, D.C., 2009, May 14-16, mss85758_140_008
    - Feulner addressing interns "Dr. Feulner Speaks to the Spring 2009 Interns." Washington, D.C., 2009, mss85758_140_016